Guide to the Martin Michel erotic films, 1940s-1973.
Michel, Martin erotic films
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Martin Michel erotic films, 1940s-1973.
7800
Michel, Martin
45 items.
Movie film
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Vintage pornographic films (16 mm, 8 mm, and super-8). Although they are mainly on gay male themes, some have heterosexual, lesbian, or pseudo-lesbian (for a heterosexual male audience) content. With the films are a few pieces of ephemera, including a mailing envelope from the Evergreen Club postmarked August 1973, and another mailer with an unopened invoice. With each film are notes made by Thomas Waugh as he was doing research for his book, Hard to imagine: Gay male eroticism in photography and film from their beginnings to Stonewall.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Vintage pornographic films (16 mm, 8 mm, and super-8). Although they are mainly on gay male themes, some have heterosexual, lesbian, or pseudo-lesbian (for a heterosexual male audience) content. With the films are a few pieces of ephemera, including a mailing envelope from the Evergreen Club postmarked August 1973, and another mailer with an unopened invoice. With each film are notes made by Thomas Waugh as he was doing research for his book, Hard to imagine: Gay male eroticism in photography and film from their beginnings to Stonewall.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Michel, Martin, 1919-1993,; Waugh, Thomas, 1948-
Subjects:
Pornographic films.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Related collection: Martin Michel papers, held at New York Public Library, Manuscripts and Archives Division.
NOTES
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- "L", 1973; F-972 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector:[= Lesbian?], 5-in reel, no can or box, but with original mailing envelop and sales receipt dated August 1973. British? Lesbian scene in limo; some hetero action later. Minimal story line. Lots of breast, little or no groin exposure; no male nudity; no fucking.
- "Variations in Love", 1973; F-973 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-inch reel, no can or box, but includes part of original mailer of July 1973 with unopened invoice still attached. 10 min. (?). Has soundtrack on 33 rpm record. Waugh’s note seems to say “Recording and printed manual also present,” but I do not have a recording and do not recall ever having it.
- “LX 9”, ca. 1970's; F-974 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in reel in original box, reg-8, color. teenager and lifeguard, ca. 1970s? age difference
- "An Anxious Maiden Gets Relief", n.d.; F-975 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: 5-in. plastic can, super8. Can is probably not original. No notes from Prof. Waugh found for this film.
- "Exchange Students", n.d.; F-976 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: 5-in. metal can, reg.-8, hetero, couple smoking, sex and books. Can possibly not original.
- "A Late Visitor", n.d.; F-977 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: 7-in. metal can, 16 mm. (formerly the second item following “Lazy Sailor”). No notes from Prof. Waugh found for this film. Can not original.
- "Love Burglar", ca. 1950's; F-978 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: 7-in. reel, no can, 16 mm. b/w, silent, heterosexual stag film ca. 1950s; burglar rapes willing female.
- "Lazy Sailor", ca. 1950's; F-979 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: AMG, 7-in. reel, no can. 16 mm, ca. 10 min., ca. late 1950s (formerly followed by “A Late Visitor” on same reel)
- "Flat Tire", ca. 1950's; F-980 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: 7-in. reel in box, reg. 8 mm., ca. 1950s, classic hetero stag film, exchange of sex for tire repair.
- "Nun Story", n.d.; F-981 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: 7-in reel in box, reg. 8 mm., classic hetero stag film. Condition: very pale.
- "Beach Frolics", ca. 1966; F-982 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: in color, 2.75-in. reel in original box. reg.-8 mm. Condition pink, but good. Boy posing by a waterfall, ca. 1966, one figure.
- "Wayne", ca. 1970; F-983 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: 2.75-in box, color, reg. 8, one figure j.o., amateur? ca. 1970, (skinny, unattractive model).
- "Stood Up", ca. 1967; F-984 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: in original 5-in. box, reg. 8, ca. 1967, has photo of two nude men glued to the box, but they are not the models in the film, who are blonde and brunette. Massage leads to anal intercourse. Waugh notes “MM [for Martin Michel?]: comment: “Extra good” [but not clear where Waugh read that as it’s not on the box]. Condition fair.
- "Daring!!", ca. 1968; F-985 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: in original 5-in box, reg. 8, ca. 1968. gay: tender, long hair, goatee. Not the models in the photo on the package. Genital-oral and then anal action. Condition: medium.
- "G101", ca. 1969; F-986 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in-reel, no box or can, reg. 8, bw, homo, ca. 1969, hardcore with lots of kissing.
- "H-One Poker Party", ca. 1969; F-987 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel, no box or can. Pickwick Films Presents, ca. 1969, bw, reg. 8. Strip poker party, good mise-en-scene at start.
- "Two English Boys and One Girl", n.d.; F-988 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: triangle. 5-in. reel, no box or can. bw, reg. 9, hetero.
- "Browning Version", ca. 1970; F-989 (Box 1)
  Notes from the collector: 5-in reel, no can, no box, bw reg. 8, homo: hippies on sofa, move to bedroom, ca. 1970.
- "Zorba", ca. 1967; F-990 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: 5-in reel, no can, no box, bw reg 8, two men and a woman, one man has Groucho glasses. British? start only.
- "Boy, Oh Boy", ca. 1967; F-991 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: 13A, Pt. 2. on 5-in reel, no box, no ca. Reg. 9, bw, ca. 1967, condition bad. Sudden start. Genital-oral action. Break in the middle. British? 2 different couples?
- "Boys Will Be Boys", ca. 1969; F-992 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: 10G. on 5-in. reel, no can, no box. reg.(?) 8, bw. ca. 1969. three brunettes: Mediterranean, reading Body and Soul magazine. Start to grope. Caressing, poppers, three-way sex.
- "Our Gang", n.d.; F-993 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel, reg-8 mm., bw. Latino youths? date? j.o., drunk narrative pretext? third, black man, mature. kissing, genital-oral action, etc. five figures, camera on side.
- "Greek Tail", ca. 1968; F-994 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: 10H on 5-in. reel, reg-8, homo. brunette in loud shirt reads Swingers mag. ca. 1968. j.o. leads to dildo. Start only.
- "Exercise Session", ca. 1970; F-995 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: P18. on 5-in reel., reg.-8, bw. Two men training in underwear in library, ca. 1970. Start only.
- "Private", ca. 1970; F-996 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel, color, reg-8, homo. ca. 1970. Amateur? mobile camera. farm setting, pissing in own mouth; forest, j.o. shower. autofellatio.
- "David 44", ca. 1960's; F-997 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in reel, bw, reg. 8. early? ca. 1960s., homo. autofellatio. KY, ski-mask? or leather? curtained set. third figure. game with erection and jock, j.o. female? no, short hair cut.
- "Big Shot 90", ca. 1965; F-998 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel, bw, reg-9, homo. KY, sex toy and second figure; boring [?] close-ups. date? ca. 1965? dildos, avoidance of faces.
- "Number Ten", ca. 1950's; F-999 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in reel. bw, reg.-8. homo hardcore. might be early. starts right in on action, inter-title: “I can take anything a cunt can take better.” Anal emphasis. title 1. KY anyone? 2. Let’s fraternize. 3. That’s it. No faces or heads. condition good; some deterioration. Money shot. Reel also includes “Ici une fable du De Cameron: Les jeux d’amour” 1950s? French ? same striped T-short as before, bathrobes, dildo, blue jeans, ca. 1969, strange peaked cap. Well photographed. Third figure, removes boxers, rim, black backdrop; 3-way sandwich, interlude repose and caressing afterwards. Final title “The End.”
- "Judo F1", Late 1960's; F-1000 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in reel, Reg8, bw, homo. Rare Asian actor, judo master in sunglasses teaches newcomer, disrobing, premature erection, funny moment of embarrassment, leads to 3-way sex. late 1960s.
- "Donnie and Clyde Pt. I, H28", ca. 1968-1969; F-1001 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in reel, reg8, bw, homo. Male drawing a long-haired model, ca. 1968-69, stripping leads to explicit sex. Condition fair.
- "Donnie and Clyde Pt. II, E108", ca. 1968-1969; F-1002 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel, bw., reg-8, homo hardcore, ca. 1969, threesome.
- "Sailor and Marine", ca. early 1960's; F-1003 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel, reg- 8, bw, homo. Walking in park, they undress, very short hair, uniforms. Marine is active cocksucker, gets fucked, j.o. at end while buddy sunbathes. ca. early 1960s??? California? Condition: continuous scratch; overexposed.
- "Cocksuckers", ca. 1967; F-1004 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel, bw, reg-8, ca. 1967. CU of two surfers staring at each other; one has tattoos. Kissing. curtain backdrop, leisurely sex. Not fully viewed.
- "100% Lust", n.d.; F-1005 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel, bw, reg-8. hetero. Two men, one woman; no framing narrative. She has stockings: old? But 1960s eye makeup. two cocks in vagina and asshole. Ends with “FIN” (French?) Condition: overexposed.
- "Sheik (A Closer Shave)", ca. 1940's; F-1006 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: 5-in reel, bw, reg-8. hetero ca. 1940s. Various eating related activities, man in fez, witty titles, fisting [?].
- "This Is the Life", ca. 1950's; F-1007 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: (or “Newspaper Couple”) 103. 5-in reel, bw, reg-8(?) hetero, 1950s. Couple reading LIFE magazine; she gets horny, leads to sex, leads back to magazines.
- "Teas Samle. NG", ca. 1965; F-1008 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 3.4-in. reel. reg-8 (?), bw, hetero. Beehive hairdo ca. 1965, all under the sheets. He tries to escape; she pulls him back. No sex.
- "Country Cousin", ca. 1950's; F-1009 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel. bw, reg-8, ca. 1950s. masked heterosexual hillbilly and city slicker play with gun. Cum shot.
- "Two Young Plus Negro", ca. mid 1960's; F-1010 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in reel. reg-9, bw. British? ca. mid-1960s. two ca. 18 years old, three-some, starts with reading, leads to daisy chain, one black figure.
- "Kinky Lovers", ca. 1967; F-1011 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in. reel in original can. reg. 8, bw. hetero, ca. 1967. British? Starts wham bang, ends with beer. Condition bad.
- "Hitchhiker", ca. 1970's; F-1012 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in reel in original box (labeled “527 reg color”). 8reg., color, homo. ca. 1970s. Shot in moving car. Blonde, brunette, toes, cum shot.
- "Nine Male Nudists", 1965; F-1013 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in reel in original box. with photo label, © 1965. bw, reg.-8, posing, boxing, fencing, chess playing. Film is crinkled half-way through.
- "Play M", ca. 1970; F-1014 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: 11, on 5-in reel in original box. Reg-8, color, hetero ca. 1970.
- "On the Floor", n.d.; F-1015 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: LA 109. on 5-in reel in original box. reg-8, color. Bellbottoms.
- "B-Males", ca. early 1970's; F-1016 (Box 2)
  Notes from the collector: on 5-in reel in original box, reg. 8, color. hard core early 1970s.